<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Quicksand presents:</title>
    <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Quicksand presents:</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ie</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 19:00:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicksand: Silvio Lorusso, Be Like Elon: Entrepreneurial Spirit, Bureaucreativity and Self-Design</title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2018-05-18-silvio-lorusso/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 19:00:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2018-05-18-silvio-lorusso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 19:00–20:30&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 18th of May 2018&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; The Brewery&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You must become an entrepreneur&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. This is the obsessive refrain one can hear at any level of society and education. But what is entrepreneurship? What&amp;rsquo;s behind the elusive notion of entrepreneurial spirit? In this Quicksand talk, Silvio Lorusso will delve into the entrepreneurial culture formalized through the work of, among others, Joseph Schumpeter, Peter Drucker and Tom Peters to show that a radical attitude, one that passionately asks for change, might not be so different from the mindset prescribed by entrepreneurialism. When one&amp;rsquo;s disposition is instrumentalized to please an expanded bureaucracy that indifferently requires to think differently, design becomes first and foremost a matter of self-design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicksand: Joey Holder presents Adcredo–The Deep Belief Network</title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2018-03-19-joey-holder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 19:00:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2018-03-19-joey-holder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 19:00–20:30&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 19th of March 2018&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Auditorium 01&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this Quicksand talk visual artist Joey Holder will present recent projects and introduce her upcoming work: Adcredo - The Deep Belief Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adcredo will investigate the construction of belief in online networks, examining the rise of unjust ideologies and fantasies, and how these are capable of affecting our worldview. The advent of digital media has shown that the world is made up of a mass of circulating, disjointed and contradictory information. This multi-dimensional communications network can be easily manipulated by online groups and individuals, which can give rise to new narratives and ideologies. Working with the Centre for Investigative Journalism and Social Psychologists the work will take the form of a speculative association, a corporation where ideologies are disseminated to manipulate people. Conspiracy theory, sci-fact and sci-fi, corporate and religious belief systems will be woven together in this multi-dimensional work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharmacolonial Connectives: Listening Session</title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2017-11-22-manuel-angel-macia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 19:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2017-11-22-manuel-angel-macia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;by-manuel-ángel-macía&#34;&gt;by Manuel Ángel–Macía&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 19:00–&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Wednesday 22nd of November&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Big Auditorium (first floor)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Quicksand lecture takes the form of a listening session on Latin American popular music. The event explores the pharmacolonial registers of psychotropics and tropical psychedelia. Puerto Rican theorist Julio Ramos coined the term pharmacoloniality to denote an inverse process of ‘colonisation’, whereby Latin American substances—sugar, tobacco, coffee, cocaine, music—are used to ‘wake up’ and stimulate European rationality. While pharmacoloniality defines the conditions of emergence of modern temporality, it also addresses the ambiguous effects and agencies of drugs as technologies of sense. Pharmacoloniality indicates how these ungovernable substances influence contemporary modes of understanding and sense-making. A turn to the aural spectrum offers potential routes towards an intoxicated political economy of sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A talk with Dan Hassler-Forest</title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2017-02-08-dan-hassler-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 18:03:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2017-02-08-dan-hassler-forest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;on-worldbuilding-as-a-political-tool&#34;&gt;ON WORLDBUILDING AS A POLITICAL TOOL&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 17:00—&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 8th of February 2017&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Big Auditorium (first floor)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dinner&lt;/strong&gt; at ~20:00&lt;br /&gt;
Design Department (second floor)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Hassler-Forest is originally from New York, and grew up in the Netherlands. He attained MA degrees in Film Studies and English Literature (cum laude) at the University of Amsterdam. After completing his undergraduate studies, he worked for several years as an editor and film reviewer, culminating in a position as editor-in-chief of the Dutch commercial film magazine Film Scene. Unsatisfied with the superficial nature of mainstream film journalism, he started teaching film and literature courses at the University of Amsterdam in 2005, meanwhile preparing a doctoral research project that combined his interests in popular film, comics cultures, and critical theory. Funded by the Huizinga Institute for Culture and History, he completed his doctoral work in 2010, successfully defending his dissertation on the Bush-era superhero movie genre in March 2011. He now works as an assistant professor of film and literature based in the English Literature department of the University of Amsterdam, and is a frequent public lecturer on contemporary film, adaptation theory, animation and digital cinema, and theoretical approaches to popular culture and cultures of globalization. All of his work is informed by a critical approach to commodity culture and globalized capitalism, with a special focus on the political and ideological implications of fantasy genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TALK WITH EMILY SEGAL</title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2017-01-18-emily-segal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 18:03:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2017-01-18-emily-segal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;on-selling-out-and-appropriation&#34;&gt;ON SELLING OUT AND APPROPRIATION&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 20:00–&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 18th of January 2017&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Big Auditorium (first floor)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Segal is an artist and brand consultant based in Berlin. She founded the trend forecasting report K-HOLE, and her work has been presented at the Serpentine Gallery, MoMA PS1, and others. She currently teaches in the Graphic Design department at the Rietveld Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A talk by Jack Self </title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2016-10-12-jack-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 18:03:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2016-10-12-jack-self/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;on-self-initiation&#34;&gt;on Self-Initiation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 20:00 – 21:00&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 12th of October 2016&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Big Auditorium (first floor)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JACK SELF is an architect and writer based in London. He is Director of the REAL foundation, as well as curator of the 2016 British Pavilion at the Venice Biennale with Shumi Bose and Finn Williams. During the Biennale, REAL launched the first issue of The Real Review, a bi-monthly magazine about architecture and spatial practice. As an editor for Strelka Press (2011-13) he developed the first print-on-demand books on architecture. He also founded Fulcrum, a free weekly “pursuing architecture and the third millennium” based at the Architectural Association in London. He edited Real Estates: Life Without Debt (Bedford Press, 2014) and is a Contributing Editor for the Architectural Review. Recently he spoke about the future of housing at the IABR 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicksand: Togetherness</title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2016-06-18-togetherness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 18:02:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2016-06-18-togetherness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 18:00–20:00&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 18th of June, 2016&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Big Auditorium (first floor)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the graduation show of 2016 Quicksand invites graduating students and external guests fitting the subject matter, to present their agenda followed by an informal conversation on their final project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to find new horizons beyond existing systems, the works of Juliette Lizotte, Monika Grūzīte &amp;amp; Arthur Röing Baer look for alternative futures – towards new forms of togetherness. After presenting their projects, the three graduating students will discuss their work under the theme of &lt;em&gt;TOGETHERNESS&lt;/em&gt; with Vinay Gupta (Hexayurt, “Resilliance Guru”), moderated by Niels van Doorn (Assistant Professor New Media Studies and Digital Culture at the University of Amsterdam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicksand: Duality</title>
      <link>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2016-06-17-duality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 18:00:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandberg.nl/design/quicksand/blog/2016-06-17-duality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 18:00–20:00&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 17th of June 2016&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Big Auditorium (first floor)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandberg Instituut, Overschiestraat 188&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The event is open to all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the graduation show of 2016 Quicksand invites graduating students and external guests fitting the subject matter, to present their agenda followed by an informal conversation on their final project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the works of Minhong Yu and Birte Veenkamp visual poetry meets its textual counterpart. Both projects opening up a dialogue about preconceptions attached to symbols, countries, borders and languages. After a presentation of their final projects the two graduating students will discuss their work under the theme of &lt;em&gt;DUALITY&lt;/em&gt; together with Saska van Stein, (director of Bureau Europa), moderated by Annelys de Vet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>